<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Vaceslav Kanukov</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Vaceslav Kanukov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 15:09:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/44965801-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 15:09:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/44965801-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>There is a popular notion circulating social media, books, and conferences that insists God created women to be delicate. As a result of this belief, some women adopt the mantra “I must take time for myself.” They equate self-care with selfishness. Yet, I’ve spent half my life serving in church ministry and have spent the other half on the fringes of Christianity. I see self-care differently.
Self-care, done properly, is not a bad thing.</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/80567301-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 10:21:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/80567301-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>At the time I wrote this article I was 23 years old and had been a believer since the age of 17. All that I knew about being a Christian was what I had picked up from the adults around me, my own experiences and reading. Even as a young woman, I realised that I would not survive in this world without the help of our Lord Jesus Christ so I can only imagine how much more difficult it must be for the young people.</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/86985942-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 13:01:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/86985942-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>We all face times when our confidence in God and his promises are shaken. Though we know God is faithful and wants to give us great and precious promises (1 Peter 5:4, KJV), still it can feel like our world has been turned upside down. The outcome of these circumstances often leaves us feeling hurt, angry, or even scared.
This week on the blog, I have invited my friend Gina Collins to share some of her experiences with us, how she re-discovered her confdence in God in the midst of those times when her world has fallen apart.</description></item><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/48896088-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 11:32:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/48896088-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>This is part of a series in which I will be answering some of the difficult questions we face as Christians, from an exegetical, Biblical perspective. In this particular series on “Is It My…”, you can read the article on the widows and orphans.
Answer The Old Testament is filled with many exhortations to care for widows, orphans, and strangers (Heb. gēr). The book of James provides us with the most explicit New Testament charge to do so; James 1:27 says, “Religion that is pure and undefiled before God, the Father, is this: to visit orphans and widows in their affliction, and to keep oneself unstained from the world.</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/36153785-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 18:59:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/36153785-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>If then you have been raised with Christ, seek the things that are above, where Christ is, seated at the right hand of God. Set your minds on things that are above, not on things that are on earth. (Colossians 3:1-2)
We are to love each other and do good to one another, without fail Let us be sympathetic, feeling for and showing concern for our fellow believers, to make their burdens our own and to share them.</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/66688016-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 15:21:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/66688016-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>It’s no secret that when people talk about heaven, they don’t always refer to the same thing. Depending on their religious background, or lack thereof, heaven can be a city, a state of mind, a location or a condition of being—even a place where one is reunited with a deceased loved one. The Bible itself reflects this diversity in how it talks about the “heavens.” Does the Bible present a unified view of heaven, or not?</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/81355328-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:21:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/81355328-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>Why should Christians evaluate what their lives are built on? There is no higher purpose in life than to know the living God and be in His family (Titus 3:5). This is His highest priority for us to fulfill. We have the chance right now to put our lives in order, to get this priority right with Him. What will be important on the Day of Judgment? What will we really want and desire when we arrive in heaven?</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/29273407-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:34:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/29273407-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>Many people are confused by what the Bible teaches about the end-times. What does Jesus teach us about the end-times? He teaches us about God’s End-Times Plan, which can be summarized in a sentence – Jesus is the goal of God’s End-Times Plan.
In this study, we will be looking at the book of Revelation, which John was told to write by Jesus (Revelation 1:1) shortly before the death of the last Roman Emperor, Domitian.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/23759685-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/23759685-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>The church has a great opportunity to be the main transformative force in society today. But it’s going to take people of action, people like you. Why? Because the current spiritual landscape of our world is showing that people are losing their religion. More people today are becoming Spiritual but Not Religious (SBNR), which means there is a natural phenomenon occurring where people are becoming more attracted to an authentic, lived out faith in comparison to the “religiously bound” approaches to God that have become more commonplace in modern-day Christianity.</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/25214955-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 15:20:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/25214955-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>One of my goals for this blog is to begin to answer the question, “what does a great church look like”? And not just that but how do we create a great church. I want to explore and introduce you to a process that I’ve been apart of that can help you to do just that. And by doing that I hope to give you clarity on the three steps to making your church successful.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/83283729-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 11:48:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/83283729-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>A pastor’s job description might read, “Work, work, work some more and somehow find the energy to give everything else you have to everyone else you know.” Of course, there is a much simpler way to summarize that job description. A pastor’s job is to love and lead God’s people to love Him. There is no more important job in the world. There is no more important job on the face of the earth.</description></item><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/25817344-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 12:17:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/25817344-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>For many years now, Christian Fundamentalists have had a bad rap. Much in the past few decades, particularly with the rise of "fringe" groups such as the Manson Family or David Koresh's Branch Davidians, the word fundamentalism has become a dirty word.
Indeed, it seems that the word has been used to describe even moderately conservative Christians, as the term fundamentalist appears to some to describe those who are particularly rigid in their views of the Bible.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/72086264-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 08:56:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/72086264-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>The rapid growth of technology, which promises to progress quickly to perfection, is also bringing the day of the perfectionist closer. On the other hand, just as the proportion of technology is increasing, there are also more and more sci-fi novels and movies that highlight the dangers posed by the progress of technology. There are more people who accept and use technology in reality, and there are also many people who are cautious and have a fear of technology.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/49892432-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 18:01:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/49892432-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>Imagine that you are having a pleasant dream. You are peacefully resting on the beach, enjoying yourself in the beautiful sunshine and a gentle breeze. Then suddenly the sky darkens and lightning flashes. Immediately after that a loud crack strikes and a huge wave rises up. A monster wave of about 100 feet (30 meters) tall comes crashing upon you. You’re knocked back and hurled through the air and then finally you crash into the water.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/89890992-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 12:45:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/89890992-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>Often times we like to convince ourselves that we’re kind. We like to believe that we’re not one of the bullies, not someone who is leaving a legacy of cruelty wherever they go. We like to think our kindness towards others is something worth boasting about.
I hate being mean to people. I do. It’s probably my biggest pet peeve with humanity. But sometimes, being nice is worse than being mean.</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/71280653-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:20:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vaceslavkanukov3.github.io/posts/71280653-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>The right to individual freedom is among the most important human rights. However, this right does not exist without restriction; hence, it must be wisely applied. Many instances of people denying others their liberties can be cited, for example the American Civil War. In this war, the government attempted to prevent slavery from being a way of life because it believed that the protection of liberty was not for its white citizens only, but also for black citizens.</description></item></channel></rss>